Guide to the Benjamin Nelson Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: General Alphabetical Files
  - New School for Social Research (Box 76)
    - Students (Box 80)
    - Student Assistants (Box 80)
    - Tape Inventory (Box 80)
  - New York (Box 81)
  - Ni (Box 82)
  - Nielson, Donald A. (Box 82)
  - No-Ny (Box 83)
  - W.W. Norton and Company, Inc. (Box 83)
  - Novak, Michael (Box 83)
  - Nye, William P. (Box 83)
  - O (Box 83)
  - Oakes, Guy (Box 83)
  - O’Dea, Thomas F. (Box 83)
  - Oelmuller, Willi (Box 83)
  - Oestereicher, Emil (Box 83)
  - Offenbacker, Deborah I. (Box 83)
  - O’Keefe, Daniel J. (Box 83)
  - Olschki, Leo S. (Box 83)
  - O’Neill, John (Box 83)
  - Orchard, Cecil C. (Box 83)
  - Orleans, Myron (Box 83)
  - Orville, Robert (Box 83)
  - Ostman, Henry (Box 83)
  - Ostow, Mortimer (Box 83)
  - Outwater, Dennis (Box 83)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 83)
  - P (Box 84)
  - Pa (Box 84)
  - Padover, Saul K. (Box 84)
  - Page, Gillian (Box 84)
  - Palmer, Robert B. (Box 84)
  - Panikkar, Raimundo (Box 84)
  - Parenti, Michael John (Box 84)
  - Parker and Son, Ltd. (Box 84)
  - Parsons, Talcott (Box 84)
  - Partisan Review (Box 84)
  - Passe, Brian (Box 84)
  - Pe (Box 84)
  - Perinbanayagam, Robert S. (Box 84)
  - Pergamon Press, Ltd. (Box 84)
  - Perrin, John (Box 84)
  - Petzling, Peter (Box 84)
  - Pf -- Pl (Box 85)
  - Philipson, Morris (Box 85)
  - Plant, Eva (Box 85)
  - Plutchik, Robert (Box 85)
  - Po (Box 85)
  - Podhurst, Robert (Box 85)
  - Polsky, Ned (Box 85)
  - Pompa, Leon (Box 85)
  - Poole Family (Box 85)
  - Popper, Karl R. (Box 85)
  - Postan, M.M. (Box 85)
  - Poster, Constance H. (Box 85)
  - Potter, Addison (Box 85)
  - Pr-Py (Box 85)
  - Praeger Publishers, Inc. (Box 85)
  - Prasad, Satya Narain (Box 85)
  - Press, Howard (Box 85)
  - Prettyman, Alfred E. (Box 85)
  - Princeton Institute for Advanced Study (Box 85)
  - Princeton University Press (Box 85)
  - Psychiatry and Social Science Review (Box 85)
  - Psychoanalysis and the Psychoanalytic Review (Box 86)
    - General (Box 86)
    - A-K (Box 86)
    - Kardiner, Abram (Box 86)
    - L (Box 86)
    - M (Box 87)
    - Maritain, Jacques (Box 87)
    - Multiprint, Inc. (Box 87)
    - N (Box 87)
    - Nelson B. (Box 87)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 87)
    - P (Box 87)
    - R-Z (Box 88)
  - Q (Box 89)
  - Qualitative Sociology (Box 89)
  - Quigley, Carroll (Box 89)
  - R (Box 89)
  - Ra (Box 89)
  - Radio and Television Stations (Box 89)
  - Radnitzky, Gerald (Box 89)
  - Random House, Inc. (Box 89)
  - Raphael, F. (Box 89)
  - Ravetz, Jerone R (Box 89)
  - Re (Box 89)
  - Red Elk, Dennis (Box 89)
  - D. Reidel Publishing Company (Box 89)
  - Reik, Louis E. (Box 89)
  - Reik, Theodor (Box 89)
  - Religion in Life (Box 89)
  - Remes, Carol (Box 89)
  - Renaissance Society of America (Box 89)
  - Renouard, Yves (Box 89)
  - Research (Box 89)
  - Rex, John Arderne (Box 89)
  - Recommendations (Box 90)
  - Rh-Ri (Box 91)
  - The Riccobono Seminar of Roman Law in America (Box 91)
  - Richardson, David B. (Box 91)
  - Riesenberg, Peter V. (Box 91)
  - Riesman, david (Box 91)
  - Ripel, Rose, Charles and Barbara (Box 91)
  - Rivero, Alice Rafaela (Box 91)
  - Ro-Roo (Box 91)
  - Robbins (Box 91)
  - Robertson, Roland (Box 91)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 91)
  - Rockman, Arnold (Box 91)
  - Rockwell, William Walker (Box 91)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano III (Box 91)
  - Ros (Box 92)
  - Rose, Arnold (Box 92)
  - Rosen, Edward (Box 92)
  - Rosen, George (Box 92)
  - Rosenbaum, Paul D. (Box 92)
  - Rosenberg, Fred (Box 92)
  - Rosenberg, Harold (Box 92)
  - Rosenthal, Arthur J. (Box 92)
  - Ross, Dorothy (Box 92)
  - Ross, Ralph Gilbert (Box 92)
  - Ross, Stanley R. (Box 92)
  - Rossi, Ino (Box 92)
  - Rossi, Paolo (Box 92)
  - Roth, Guenther (Box 92)
  - Rot-Roz (Box 92)
  - Rothenberg, Avrum H. and Aron (Box 92)
  - Rounds, John Cary (Box 92)
  - Routledge and Kegan Paul, Ltd. (Box 92)
  - Rowen, Herbert H. (Box 92)
  - Ru-Ry (Box 93)
  - Rubenstein, Richard L. (Box 93)
  - Rubin, Julius Herman (Box 93)
  - Ruegg, Walter (Box 93)
  - Ruintbeek, Hendrik M. (Box 93)
  - S (Box 94)
  - Sa (Box 94)
  - St. Clair, Margaret (Box 94)
  - Sanders, Jerry W. (Box 94)
  - Sapori, Armando (Box 94)
  - Saveth, Edward M. (Box 94)
  - Sayanagi, Jumio J. (Box 94)
  - Sc-Schm (Box 94)
  - Schapiro, Meyer (Box 94)
  - Schechner, Richard (Box 94)
  - Schendler, David (Box 94)
  - Schendler, Evelyn J. (Box 94)
  - Schmitt, Charles M. (Box 94)
  - Schn-Scu (Box 94)
  - Schneider, Louis (Box 94)
  - Schoenhof's Foreign Books, Inc. (Box 94)
  - Schroyer, Trent (Box 94)
  - Schubert, Hans A. (Box 94)
  - Schwartz, Moshe (Box 94)
  - Schwartzman, David (Box 94)
  - Scripps College--Merlan Lecture, 1973 (Box 94)
  - Scriver, Michael (Box 94)
  - Se (Box 95)
  - Sears, Sallie (Box 95)
  - Seeley, John R. (Box 95)
  - Seger-Coulborn, Imogen (Box 95)
  - Segers, Mary C. (Box 95)
  - Seidman, Steven (Box 95)
  - Selvin, Hanan C. (Box 95)
  - Setton, Kenneth M. (Box 95)
  - Sha-She (Box 96)
  - Shaftel, Oscar H. (Box 96)
  - Shapiro, Gilbert (Box 96)
  - Shaughnessy, Edward J. (Box 96)
  - Shepherd, William C. (Box 96)
  - Shepps, Judith Wendy (Box 96)
  - Sherman, Murray H. (Box 96)
  - Sherwood, Sylvia (Box 96)
  - Shi-Shu (Box 96)
  - Shils, Edward (Box 96)
  - Shirk, Evelyn Urban (Box 96)
  - Shor, Joel (Box 96)
  - Si (Box 97)
  - Sibley, Mulford Q. (Box 97)
  - Siegel, Sidney (Box 97)
  - Siegelman, Philip (Box 97)
  - Sills, David L. (Box 97)
  - Silver, Allen (Box 97)
  - Silverman, Hugh J. (Box 97)
  - Silverman, Simon (Box 97)
  - Silvers, Robert B. (Box 97)
  - Simon, Walter B. (Box 97)
  - Simpson, Thomas (Box 97)
  - Singer, Milton B. (Box 97)
  - Sivin, Nathan (Box 97)
  - Sk (Box 98)
  - Sl (Box 98)
  - Slaner, Philip A. (Box 98)
  - Slater, Joseph Elliott (Box 98)
  - Sm-Sn (Box 98)
  - Smelser, Neil J. (Box 98)
  - Smith, Arthur A. (Tony) (Box 98)
  - (Peter) Smith Publisher, Inc. (Box 98)
  - Smith, Willie B. Lamousé (Box 98)
  - Snizek, William E. (Box 98)
  - So (Box 98)
  - Social Research (Box 98)
  - Social Science Quarterly (Box 98)
  - Society for International Development (Box 98)
  - Society for the Scientific Study of Religion (Box 99-100)
  - Society for the Study of Social Problems (Box 10l)
  - Sociological Abstracts (Box 10l)
  - Sommer, David (Box 10l)
  - Southern Oregon State College (Box 10l)
  - Sp-Sr (Box 10l)
  - Spiegel, Leo Angelo and Nancy T. (Box 10l)
  - Spiegler, Robert (Box 10l)
  - Sponitz, Hyman (Box 10l)
  - Sta (Box 10l)
  - Stabell, Timothy D. (Box 10l)
  - Stackhouse, Max L. (Box 10l)
  - Stammer, Otto (Box 10l)
  - Stanley, Manfred (Box 10l)
  - Starr, Joshua (Box 10l)
  - Staude, John-Raphael (Box 10l)
  - Staudinger, Hans (Box 10l)
  - Stavis, Barrie (Box 10l)
  - Ste (Box 102)
  - G.F. Stechert & Co. (Box 102)
  - Steeman, Theo M. (Box 102)
  - Stehr, Nico (Box 102)
  - Stein, Maurice R. (Box 102)
  - Steingesser, Martin (Box 102)
  - Stern E. Mark (Box 102)
  - Stern, Samuel (Box 102)
  - Stevens, Herbert Howe, Jr. (Box 102)
  - Stevens, Richard L. (Box 102)
  - Stevenson, Adlai Ewing--1952 Campaign (Box 102)
  - Sti (Box 102)
  - Sto (Box 102)
  - Stock, Brian (Box 102)
  - Stoehr, Taylor (Box 102)
  - Str-Stu (Box 102)
  - Strand, K. Aa. (Box 102)
  - Strean, Herbert S. (Box 102)
  - Strickler, Eileen (Box 102)
  - Stroup, Alice T. and Timothy (Box 102)
  - Strozier, Charles B. (Box 102)
  - Stuart, J.R. (Box 102)
  - Su-Sz (Box 102)
  - Sugarman, Shirley (Box 102)
  - Sullivan, John Joseph (Box 102)
  - Sutherland, David Earl (Box 102)
  - Swann Auction Galleries (Box 102)
  - T (Box 103)
  - Ta-Te (Box 103)
  - Tagliacozzo, Daisy M. (Box 103)
  - Tanenbaum, Marc H. (Box 103)
  - Tapp, Robert B. (Box 103)
  - Tauber, Jacob and Susan (Box 103)
  - Tax, Sol (Box 103)
  - Teitler, Marcel (Box 103)
  - Tenbruck, Freidrich H. and Kora (Box 103)
  - Teschendorf, Melvin Charles (Box 103)
  - Th (Box 103)
  - Thackray, Arnold Wilfred (Box 103)
  - Theodorsen, George A. (Box 103)
  - Thomes, A. Boyd and Maris (Box 103)
  - Thorner, Daniel (Box 103)
  - Thumin, Eugene (Box 103)
  - Ti -- Tk (Box 104)
  - Tillich, Paul and Hannah (Box 104)
  - Tiryakian, Edward A. (Box 104)
  - To (Box 104)
  - Tobias, Mervyn (Box 104)
  - Tr (Box 104)
  - Traum, Samuel (Box 104)
  - Trexler, Richard C. (Box 104)
  - Trinkaus, Charles (Box 104)
  - Tu-Ty (Box 104)
  - Tu, Wei-ming (Box 104)
  - Tuchman, Marcel (Box 104)
  - Turkle, Sherry Roxanne (Box 104)
  - Turner, Frederick (Box 104)
  - Turner, Victor (Box 104)
  - Turner, Terence (Box 104)
  - Tuveson, Ernest (Box 104)
  - Tymieniecka, Anna-Teresa (Box 104)
  - U (Box 105)
  - Unguari, Tamas (Box 105)
  - Union of America Hebrew Congregation (Box 105)
  - Union Theological Seminary (Box 105)
  - U.S. (Government Agencies) (Box 105)
  - University Microfilms, Inc. (Box 105)
  - Urizen Books, Inc. (Box 105)
  - V (Box 105)
  - Vallier, Ivan (Box 105)
  - Van der Haag, Ernest (Box 105)
  - Varma, Baidya Nath (Box 105)
  - Velikovsky, Immanuel (Box 105)
  - Vidich, Arthur J. (Box 105)
  - Von Mering, Otto (Box 105)
  - Von Grunebaum, Giselle E.S. and Gustave E. (Box 105)
  - W (Box 106)
  - Wa (Box 106)
  - Wachsman, Arthur A. (Box 106)
  - Wagner, Helmut R. (Box 106)
  - Walker, Nigel (Box 106)
  - Wallace, William A. (Box 106)
  - Wallwork, Ernest E. (Box 106)
  - Walsh, Robert W.J. (Box 106)
  - Walter, Eugene Victor (Box 106)
  - Wangh, Martin (Box 106)
  - Wardwell, Walter S. (Box 106)
  - Warmbrand, Martin J. (Box 106)
  - Warner, R. Stephen (Box 106)
  - Warren, Alexandra (Box 106)
  - Warren, Larissa Bonfante (Box 106)
  - Wartofsky, Marx W. (Box 106)
  - Washington, Robert Earl (Box 106)
  - Washington Square Consultation Center (Box 106)
  - Watson, Goodwin (Box 106)
  - Wax, Murray (Box 106)
  - Wayne State University (and WSU Press) (Box 106)
  - We (Box 107)
  - Weil, Helen H. (Box 107)
  - Weingart, Peter (Box 107)
  - Weinstein, Fred (Box 107)
  - Weisinger, Herbert (Box 107)
  - Weiss, Daniel A. (Box 107)
  - Weiss, John (Box 107)
  - Weitman, Sasha (Box 107)
  - Wekerle, Frank (Box 107)
  - Wescott, Roger W. (Box 107)
  - Wh (Box 107)
  - Wheelis, Allen B. (Box 107)
  - White, Lynne Jr. (Box 107)
  - White, Morton Gabriel (Box 107)
  - Whitley, Richard D. (Box 107)
  - Wi (Box 108)
  - Widmer, Eleanor Joan Rackow Nelson (Box 108)
  - Wiley and Sons Inc., Publishers (Box 108)
  - Wieck, Fred (see also Harper and Row) (Box 108)
  - Wienpohl, Paul D. (Box 108)
  - Wilcox, Elizabeth (Box 108)
  - Willems, Emilio (Box 108)
  - Williams J. Paul (Box 108)
  - Williams, Jay C. (Box 108)
  - Willman, Frederick J. (Box 108)
  - Winckelmann, Johannes (Box 108)
  - Winick, Charles (Box 108)
  - Winthrop, Henry (Box 108)
  - Withim, Philip (Box 108)
  - Wittenberg, Ulrike (Box 108)
  - Wo (Box 109)
  - Wohl, R. Richard (Box 109)
  - Wolf, Charles Parker (Box 109)
  - Wolff, Kurt H. (Box 109)
  - Wolff, Michael (Box 109)
  - Wolfson, Harry A. (Box 109)
  - Wolfman, Benjamin B. (Box 109)
  - Woltmann, Adolf G. (Box 109)
  - Workshop Institute for Living-Learning (Box 109)
  - The World Publishing Co. (Meridian Books) (Box 109)
  - Wr-Wy (Box 109)
  - Wrong, Dennis H. (Box 109)
  - Wyschogrod, Edith (Box 109)
  - Y (Box 110)
  - Yocum, Doris E. (Box 110)
  - Young, Estelle (Box 110)
  - Y.M.H.A. (Box 110)
  - Z (Box 110)
  - Zaslovsky, Robert (Box 110)
  - Zerin, Edward and Wendy (Box 110)
  - Zilderveld, Anton C. (Box 110)
  - Zito, George Vincent (Box 110)
- Series III: Conferences, 1950-1978
  - Conferences
    - 1950-1959 and undated (Box 111)
    - 1961-1966 (Box 112)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 113)
    - 1970 (Box 114)
    - 1971 (Box 115)
    - 1972 (Box 116)
    - 1973 (Box 117-118)
    - 1974 (Box 119)
- Series IV: Manuscripts and Notes
  - A-B (Box 123)
  - C (Box 124)
  - Civilization (Box 125)
  - Conscience (1) (Box 126-217)
  - Copernicus (Box 128)
  - Course notes (1) (Box 129-131)
  - D-E (Box 132)
  - Economic history (cards) (Box 133)
  - F (Box 134)
  - G-Galileo (Box 135)
  - Galileo
    - Galileo--General and A-B (Box 135)
    - Galileo--C-E (Box 136)
    - Galileo--F-P (Box 137)
    - Galileo--R-Z (Box 138)
  - H-I (Box 139)
  - The Idea of Usury
    (Box 140 contains printed copies of The Idea of Usury. Box 152 contains the most complete typescript version of the early state of Nelson's Columbia PhD thesis: The Restitution of Usury [early 1940s] which was the basis for the later shortened version published in 1949 as The Idea of Usury .)
    - The Idea of Usury--General (Box 140-153)
    - The Idea of Usury--A (Box 154)
    - The Idea of Usury--B (Box 155)
    - The Idea of Usury--Ca (Box 156)
    - The Idea of Usury--Ch-Cu (Box 157)
    - The Idea of Usury--D (Box 158)
    - The Idea of Usury--E-F (Box 159)
    - The Idea of Usury--G-I (Box 160)
    - The Idea of Usury--J (Box 161)
    - The Idea of Usury--K-L (Box 162)
    - The Idea of Usury--M (Box 163)
    - The Idea of Usury--N-P (Box 164)
    - The Idea of Usury--R-S (Box 165)
    - The Idea of Usury--T-Z (Box 166)
    - The Idea of Usury--cards (Box 167-182)
    - The Idea of Usury--cards--'Economic history' (Box 183)
    - The Idea of Usury--cards--'Italy' (Box 184-185)
    - The Idea of Usury--cards--'Wills and testaments' (Box 186-188)
  - J-Mad (Box 189)
  - Mai-Marl (Box 190)
  - Marx-Men (Box 191)
  - Merchant of Venice (Box 192-193)
  - Mert-My (Box 194)
  - N (Box 195)
  - O-Pe (Box 196)
  - Personality, work, community: an introduction to social science (Box 197-200, 200A)
  - Pe-Po (Box 201)
  - Pr-Ra (Box 202)
  - Re (Box 203)
  - Ri-Sc (Box 204)
  - Se-Sl (Box 205)
  - So (Box 206)
  - Mss & notes: Sp-Th (Box 207)
  - Ti-Z (Box 208)
  - Weber, Max (Box 209)
    - General and A-B (Box 209)
    - The brother and the other (Box 210)
    - C-F (Box 211)
    - G-J (Box 212)
    - K-L (Box 213)
    - M-R (Box 2l4)
    - S-W (Box 215)
  - Mss & notes: Miscellaneous (Box 2l6-219)
  - 'General' cards (Box 220-221)
  - Lectures (Box 222)
  - Notebooks (Box 223)
  - Books (Box 224)
  - - (Box 224)